So there are a couple of really useful phrases that we can use to talk about fitness.
因此，我们可以使用一些非常有用的短语来谈论健身。
We're going to talk about fitness because in a moment I'm going to give you an example of how we can
我们将谈论健身，因为稍后我将给您举一个例子，说明我们如何做到
ask for advice about losing weight right.
寻求有关减肥的建议。
We don't want to be so fat.
我们不想这么胖。
How one friend might ask another friend and then how we can give advice about that before we do we have
一位朋友如何询问另一位朋友，然后我们如何在这之前给出建议
to go over a couple of useful words and phrases.
复习一些有用的单词和短语。
OK.
好的。
So get in shape is when we're not in shape.
所以保持身材就是我们没有身材的时候。
So being in shape means maybe you are fit which means maybe you have some muscle.
所以保持身材意味着也许你很健康，这意味着也许你有一些肌肉。
Maybe you don't have so much fat.
也许你没有那么多脂肪。
Maybe you can run without getting out of breath.
也许你可以跑步而不会气喘吁吁。
Maybe your heart is in a good condition right.
也许你的心脏状况良好吧。
Maybe you can exercise without getting tired.
也许你可以锻炼而不累。
You are fit.
你很合适。
You are in shape.
你的身材很好。
It's not only about being thin.
这不仅仅是关于瘦。
It's not only about being fat it's more than that.
这不仅是关于胖，还不止于此。
You can be very very thin and very very out of shape.
你可以非常非常瘦，非常非常变形。
So I want to make it clear that thinness being slender is not the same as being in shape being in shape
所以我想明确一点，瘦瘦不等于有型有型
includes strength includes some muscle.
包括力量包括一些肌肉。
OK.
好的。
Same with same with fitness.
健身也一样。
Getting fit.
变得健康。
Same thing.
一样。
These are the same.
这些都是一样的。
OK.
好的。
Now lose weight.
现在减肥。
What we really mean here is lose fat.
我们在这里真正的意思是减脂。
That's what it means.
这就是它的意思。
We often say lose weight.
我们常说减肥。
I want to lose weight.
我想减肥。
It's just a convenient way to say lose fat.
这只是说减肥的一种方便的方式。
We don't say lose fat.
我们不说减脂。
Usually this is a little different than these two because you could lose weight because maybe you got
通常这与这两个有点不同，因为你可以减肥，因为也许你得到了
really really ill or he's lost so much weight because of maybe the illness that would be a terrible
真的病得很重，或者他体重减轻了很多，因为可能是一种可怕的疾病
thing.
事物。
But are you fit.
但是你适合吗。
Probably not.
可能不是。
No you're not fat but you're also not fit.
不，你不胖，但你也不健康。
OK.
好的。
So losing weight is more general and this one is just about fat basically.
所以减肥是比较普遍的，这个基本上就是胖了。
Put on weight or put on a few.
增加重量或增加一些重量。
And sometimes we can say a few pounds a few pounds put on a few pounds over Christmas.
有时我们可以说几磅几磅在圣诞节增加几磅。
I really put on a few pounds over Christmas.
我真的在圣诞节增加了几磅。
I really put on some weight.
我真的增加了一些体重。
Maybe you can see from the previous courses I've done that now I've I've put on a few I've put on a
也许你可以从我以前做过的课程中看到，现在我已经放了一些我放了一个
few.
很少。
Maybe you can tell from my my face compared to the previous courses the English brain ones and the pronunciation
也许你可以从我的脸上看出与以前的课程相比，英语大脑和发音
ones that I did before.
我以前做过的那些。
OK.
好的。
So these are very common ways to talk about our condition and we have a few other specific words as
所以这些是谈论我们状况的非常常见的方式，我们还有其他一些具体的词作为
well.
出色地。
So let's look at those really quickly in America being very direct about somebody whose weight is not
所以让我们看看那些在美国非常直接的人
always a good thing and someone might be a little offended if you say she's fat he's fat.
总是一件好事，如果你说她胖他胖，有人可能会有点生气。
Even if they are what you might describe as fat there's just something about the culture and it's good
即使他们是你可能描述为肥胖的东西，也有一些关于文化的东西，这很好
to know because if you say it too much people might feel a little offended.
要知道，因为如果你说得太多，人们可能会觉得有点被冒犯了。
So we can say some other words a little bit is chubby someone is chubby they have some fat not so much.
所以我们可以说一些其他的词有点胖，有些人胖，他们有一些脂肪而不是那么多。
Not very very fat but we can describe them as chubby or a bit chubby.
不是很胖，但我们可以将它们描述为胖乎乎的或有点胖乎乎的。
We can also describe someone as overweight you're overweight you're a bit overweight I think you need
我们也可以将某人描述为超重 你超重 你有点超重 我认为你需要
to go on a diet.
去节食。
OK so overweight means there they have too much fat they're too heavy they're more heavy than they should
好吧，所以超重意味着他们有太多的脂肪他们太重了他们比他们应该的更重
be they're heavier than they should be overweight.
是他们比他们应该超重更重。
This one's pretty common but this is more than this one.
这个很常见，但不止这个。
This one is usually fatter than this one.
这个通常比这个胖。
Now someone might describe someone who is fat as heavy.
现在有人可能会形容一个胖的人很重。
It's actually a more polite way to say it.
这实际上是一种更礼貌的说法。
So if you said Oh yeah you're your uncle's he's a bit heavy.
所以如果你说哦，是的，你是你叔叔的，他有点重。
Right.
正确的。
He's a bit heavy isn't he.
他是不是有点重。
Yeah he's he's a bit heavy.
是的，他有点重。
Sometimes we say heavy set heavy set.
有时我们说重集重集。
She's she's quite a lot heavier than she used to be.
她比以前重了很多。
Wow.
哇。
It's more polite than saying She's fatter than she used to be.
这比说她比以前更胖更有礼貌。
Your uncle is very fat right.
你叔叔很胖吧。
So saying fat is kind of like hitting somebody in the head with maybe truth maybe real information but
所以说胖有点像用可能的真相或真实的信息打某人的头，但是
in a way that makes them feel maybe not so good so often use heavy sometimes overweight sometimes chubby.
以某种方式让他们感觉可能不太好，所以经常使用沉重的有时超重有时胖乎乎的。
And it's interesting how in different cultures what is fat is described differently.
有趣的是，在不同的文化中，脂肪是如何被不同的描述的。
I've noticed for example that someone who might be considered normal in America in a lot of Asian countries
例如，我注意到在许多亚洲国家的美国可能被认为是正常的人
like China for example that person might be considered fat and even if you've got a little fat someone
比如中国，那个人可能会被认为是胖子，即使你有点胖
in China might say oh you're fat it's a different culture.
在中国可能会说哦，你很胖，这是一种不同的文化。
That's quite interesting.
这很有趣。